<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protocol name="zen_desktop">
  <copyright>
    MIT License

    Copyright (c) 2022 Akihiro Kiuchi &amp; Taishi Eguchi

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person
    obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files
    (the "Software"), to deal in the Software without restriction,
    including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge,
    publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software,
    and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so,
    subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be
    included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
    EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF
    MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND
    NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS
    BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN
    ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN
    CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE
    SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>
  <interface name="zen_display_system" version="1">
    <description summary="a singleton managing display system">
      A singleton global object through which clients can manage zen's display
      system, which manages how the desktop environment is presented to the
      user. For example, it can be presented in VR.
    </description>

    <enum name="error">
      <description summary="zen_display_system error values"/>
      <entry name="no_immersive_device" value="0" summary="No device found for immersive display"/>
    </enum>

    <enum name="type">
      <description summary="display system type"/>
      <entry name="screen" value="0" summary="display desktop environment with physical screens"/>
      <entry name="immersive" value="1" summary="display desktop environment with immersive display"/>
    </enum>

    <request name="switch_type">
      <description summary="switch display system type">
        Request a server to switch display system type.
      </description>
      <arg name="type" type="uint" enum="type"/>
    </request>

    <event name="applied">
      <description summary="new display system type applied">
        Notification that a new display system type has been applied.
      </description>
      <arg name="type" type="uint" enum="type" summary="new display system type"/>
    </event>

    <request name="release" type="destructor">
      <description summary="release the zen_display_system object">
        Using this request, a client can tell the server that the client is not
        going to use the zen_display_system anymore.
      </description>
    </request>
  </interface>
</protocol>
